Guide to the Pierson College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Pierson College, Yale University, records of the master
1931-1970
RU 316
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
17
The records consist of correspondence, budget materials, and subject files documenting student activities and accomplishments, scholarships, athletics, and student employment.
Pierson College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-J-2 (YRG 13-J-2), Records of the master of Pierson College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, budget materials, and subject files documenting student activities and accomplishments, scholarships, athletics, and student employment.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
College students; Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Pierson College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Records, 1931-1962; Accession 19ND-A-309
  - Allocations, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allocations (lists), 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Athletics (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Athletics: 'Statistical Summary of Exercise Activities, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Atheltics: Intercollege, Freshman Intramural, Graduate School, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bursary Appointments, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Records
    - 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1933 Jan - Jun (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1933 Jul - Dec (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1934 Jan - Mar (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1934 Apr - Sep (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1934 Oct - Dec (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1935 Jan - Mar (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1935 Apr - Sep (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 1935 Oct - Dec (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 1936 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1937 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1938 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1940 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - no date (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - A-K, 1942-62 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - L-R, 1942-62 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - S-Z, 1942-62 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Fellows, 1933-35 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Library, 1935-37 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lists, 1934-37 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1932-36 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Questionnaire, 1936-37 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Receipts, 1933-36 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Receipts, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Rooms: lists, 1938-39 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Scholarships, 1933-34 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Scholarship Contracts, 1934-35 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Scholarhsips, 1935-36 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Scholarship Contracts, 1935-36 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Scholarship Contracts, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Council of Masters' records, 1939-1970; Accession 1972-A-007
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2046
  - Minutes
    - 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
    - 1951-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1-13)
  - General, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bellamy Prize, 1939-1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Janitors and guards, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Financial Aid, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Permissions and notices, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Memos, minutes, correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Personnel, 1947-1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - College plan, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pierson Fellowship: proposals, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Committee on Allocations, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, rules, etc., 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pierson file, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
  - Meeting minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)